The female connector has bayonet slots on the inside.
Connect a hose of fitting size with a worm drive clamp (not shown).
Insert the male connector lugs into the slots of the female one.
Twist to close as indicated on the outside of the connector.
Twist in reverse to unlock the connection.
Remove the hose from the female connector by pulling,
possibly applying tension in the open direction.
You can specify any hose diameter that fits onto your build plate.
The same goes for the hose fitting length, limited by the build volume you have.
The 3MF you download from customization has a plate for each part.
Good luck with printing your parts!